Guide to the Jack Gelber Papers 1938-2002 (Bulk 1957-1999) MSS.146
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Subseries A
    - Helena Strassova Representant d'Auteurs et d'Editeurs Francais et Etrangers, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 278)
    - Heller, Joe, Undated (Box 5, Folder 279)
    - Hellman, Jerome, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 280)
    - Helsingin Yliopisto, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 281)
    - Henderson, Don, Undated (Box 5, Folder 282)
    - [Hents, Nat], Undated (Box 5, Folder 283)
    - [Hiee], Holly, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 284)
    - Hill and Wang, 1972-1975 (Box 5, Folder 285)
    - Hildebrand, Karen, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 286)
    - [Hiss], Isabel, Undated (Box 5, Folder 287)
    - Hitchcock, George, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 288)
    - Hoffenberg, Mason, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 289)
    - Hoffman, Dustin, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 290)
    - Holbrook, Gerald C., [1971] (Box 5, Folder 291)
    - Holbrook, Hal, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 292)
    - Holland America Line, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 293)
    - Hollander, Jack K., 1977 (Box 5, Folder 294)
    - Howard, Maureen, Undated (Box 5, Folder 295)
    - Hughes, Tresa, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 296)
    - Hurst, Lillian, 1968-1976 (Box 5, Folder 297)
    - Hoover, Richard, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 298)
    - House, Rain, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 299)
    - Hull House Association, 1963, Undated (Box 5, Folder 300)
    - Hyperion Books, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 301)
    - Institute for Contemporary Psychotherapy, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 302)
    - Institute of International Education, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 303)
    - INTAR: Hispanic American Arts Center, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 304)
    - International Association for the Defense of Artists, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 305)
      The contents of this folder include a photocopy of "Letter to the Editor: A Czech Playwright Who Should Be Freed," Jack Gelber et al, New York Times, July 10, 1981
    - International Creative Management, 1968-1979 (Box 5, Folder 306)
      The contents of this folder include a signed agreement offering Gelber the position of Director for a production of "Eulogy for a Small Time Thief" by Miguel Pinero
    - International Drama Agency, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 307)
    - Intuitions, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 308)
    - Israel, Ann, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 309)
    - Israel, David K., 1972 (Box 5, Folder 310)
    - The Ivar Theatre, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 311)
      This folder also holds an unsigned contract regarding "The Connection"
    - Jain, Jasbir, 1983, Undated (Box 5, Folder 312)
    - Jeffrey Richards Associates, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 313)
      The contents of this folder include the following clippings: "The Rites of Refusal," Howard Kissel, Daily News, February 5, 1993, "Guilty Charges for All Germans," Clive Barnes, New York Post Weekend, January 29, 1993, "At Large: The Sins of Nazi Fathers," Wilborn Hampton, The New York Times, January 28, 1993, "Born Guilty," Greg Evans, Variety, February 1, 1993, "'Born Guilty' Opens Off Broadway," Mary Campbell, Associated Press, January 24, 1993, "Memory's Truths and Memory's Lies," Miriam Rinn, [The Forward], January 22, 1993,"Confronting Nazi Legacy," Aileen Jacobson, New York Nesdday, January 26, 1993, "Born Guilty," Humanites News, Vol. 10 No. 20, January 26, 1992, "'Born Guilty;' Can Wolves Turn Into Sheep?" Miriam Rinn, The Guide, January 29, 1993, "Punch In International Syndicate Release," Laurie Lawson, n.d., "Play Takes Relentless Look at German Family's Guilt," The Jewish Week, Inc., January 29-February 4, 1993, "Born Guilty," Newsday, January 24, 1993, "German's and Jews: Memory and Conscience," The Guide, January 15, 1993, "A Baker's Audition," David Lefkowitz, Stages, January-February 1993, and "New York, New York: A Baker's Audition," Michael Sander, Drama-Logue, January 14-20, 1993
    - Jenkins, Len, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 314)
    - Jerry, Susan Mann, Malisa, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 315)
    - The John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 316)
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1963-1990 (Box 5, Folder 317)
    - Johnson, Nick, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 318)
    - John Springer Associates, Inc., 1965 (Box 5, Folder 319)
      The contents of this folder include the following clippings: "Theatre: 'Square In the Eye," Women's Wear Daily, May 20, 1965, "Jack Gelber's Upside Down World," Maurice R. Berube, United Teacher Vol. 6 No. 16, June 14, 1965, "Jack Gelber's New Play," Labor Chronicle, May 1965, "Square in the Eye is Dull, Draggy Dramatics," James Davis, Daily News, May 20 1965, "Jack Gelber Looks at Urban Life," Richard Watts Jr., New York Post, May 20, 1965, "'Square in the Eye' Rates Absolute Zero," Wiiliam A. Raidy, [Newhouse Papers], May 20, 1965, "Theatre: Square in the Eye," The Village Voice, May 27, 1965, "The Theatre," Leota Diesel, The Villager, June 3, 1965, Untitled, N.Y. Staats-Zeitung und Herold, June 1, 1965, "Intellectual Twister," Time, May 28, 1965, "Whirligig," Newsweek, May 28, 1965, "Square in the Eye," Cue, May 29, 1965, "1st Add Night Lead Review New York," Limited Press International, May 19, 1965, Untitled, Mary Campbell, Associated Press, May 19, 1965, "Review: Square in the Eye," Maxine Keith, WNYC, May 19, 1965, Untitled, Lou Kleinman, WRVR-FM, May 21, 1965, Untitled, John Wongate, WOR-TV, May 19, 1965, "The Theatre," Norman Nadel, New York World Telegram and Sun, Undated, "Theatre: Play by Gelber," Howard Taubman, The New York Times, May 20, 1965, "Hip-Slang Play Isn't Ver Hip," Jack Thompson, Journal-American, May 20, 1965, "Kerr: 'Square in the Eye,'" New York Herald Tribune, May 20, 1965, and "Gelber Comedy Opens in the Theatre de Lys," George Oppenheimer, Newsday, May 20, 1965; See Also: "Biography of Jack Gelber" by Unknown Author (Annotated Typescript) (Series IIS, Box 45, Folder 1174)
    - John Stark Productions, Ltd., 1968-1975, Undated (Box 5, Folder 320)
    - Joseph M. Gottfried and Company, Certified Public Accountants, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 321)
    - Jowdy, Jefferson, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 322)
    - Joy, John, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 323)
    - Julia, Merel, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 324)
    - K., Marty, Undated (Box 5, Folder 325)
    - Kahn, Judd, Undated (Box 5, Folder 326)
    - Kain, Frank, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 327)
    - Kalom, Ron, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 328)
    - Kanterman, Leroy, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 329)
    - Kaplan, Jeanne, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 330)
    - Karmel, Alex Karmel, Marjie, 1961-1978 (Box 6, Folder 331)
    - Karwowski, Robert J., 1980 (Box 6, Folder 332)
    - Kauffman, J. Patrick, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 333)
    - Keach, Stacy, Undated (Box 6, Folder 334)
    - Kelley, Gordon P., 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 335)
    - Kennedy, Senator Robert F., 1968 (Box 6, Folder 336)
    - Kenneth W. Lampert Insurance, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 337)
    - Kent State University, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 338)
      See Also: Bank, Rosemarie K., Dr. (Series IA, Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Kestenbaum, Granvilette Williams, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 339)
    - Kirshenbaum, Binnie, 1987-1997 (Box 6, Folder 340)
    - Kitchen Company, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 341)
      The contents of this folder include a signed contract offering Gelber the position of Director for a production of "The Kitchen" by Arnold Wesker
    - Kliman, Jeffrey, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 342)
    - Kolo, Fred H., 1990 (Box 6, Folder 343)
    - Konecky, Isobel Robins Konecky, Ronald S., 1968-1987, Undated (Box 6, Folder 344)
      The contents of this folder include a copy of a signed contract regarding "Sleep" and copies of outgoing letters to various producers and theatre directors such as Avco Embassy Pictures Corporation and Alhark
    - Koningsberger, Hans, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 345)
    - Kopit, Arthur, 1967-1968, Undated (Box 6, Folder 346)
    - Kopit, George Kopit, Maxine, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 347)
    - Korno, Erika, [1968] (Box 6, Folder 348)
    - Kostelanetz, Richard, 1972-1986 (Box 6, Folder 349)
    - Kra, Andrew, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 350)
    - Kramer, Mary, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 351)
    - Krementz, Jill, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 352)
    - Kussmaul, Dorothy, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 353)
    - Kustow, Michael, 1970-1977 (Box 6, Folder 354)
    - Lacy, Catherine, Undated (Box 6, Folder 355)
    - LaH Film Corporation, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 356)
    - Lahr, Anthea, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 357)
    - Lahti, Christine, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 358)
    - [Lamb], Phil, 1987-1998 (Box 6, Folder 359)
      See Also: Robert P. Reiter Attorney at Law (Series IA, Box 9, Folder 545), Tufts University (Series IA, Box 11, Folder 678)
    - Larangeira, Crispin, 1979-1981 (Box 6, Folder 360)
    - Law Offices of Cohn, Glickstein, Lurie, Ostrin, Lubell, and Lubell, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 361)
    - Law Offices of Kaplan, Livingston, Goodwin, Berkowitz, and Selvin, 1971-1981 (Box 6, Folder 362)
    - Law Offices of Litvinoff and Singer, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 363)
    - Lawrence, Marcia, Undated (Box 6, Folder 364)
    - League of Resident Theatres, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 365)
    - Lederer, William, 1976-1984, Undated (Box 6, Folder 366)
    - Lefkowitz, Debra, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 367)
    - Leibman, Ron, Undated (Box 6, Folder 368)
    - Leigh, Vivien, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 369)
    - Lerman, Leo, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 370)
    - Levine, Howard L., 1989 (Box 6, Folder 371)
    - Levinson, Barry, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 372)
    - Lewis, Bob, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 373)
    - Lifestyles Magazine, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 374)
      The contents of this folder include a draft of "Jack Gelber" by Jerry Tallmer with annotations by Jack Gelber
    - Lifton, Mitchell, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 375)
    - Lincoln Center Theatre, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 376)
    - Litag Theaterverlag GmbH, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 377)
    - Litvinoff, Seymour, 1960-1975, Undated (Box 6, Folder 378)
      The contents of this folder include the following clippings: "Random Notes on This and That," Richard Watts, Jr., New York Post, February 18, 1964, "'Connection' Hailed at Cannes," unknown author, The New York Times; and copies of outgoing letters to and original letters received from various producers including a signed contract with The Living Theatre Productions, Inc. for "The Connection;" See Also: Actor's Theatre (Series IA, Box 1, Folder 6), Samuel French, Inc. (Series IA, Box10, Folder 570), United States Department of the Treasury (Series IA, Box 11, Folder 687)
    - The Living Theatre, 1959-1989 (Box 6, Folder 379)
    - Locklin, Gerry, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 380)
    - Lockwood, Lee, 1966-1971, Undated (Box 6, Folder 381)
    - Loggia, Marjorie, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 382)
    - Long Wharf Theatre, 1975-1987 (Box 7, Folder 383)
    - Los Angeles Actor's Theatre, 1981-1984 (Box 7, Folder 384)
      See Also: [Bingos, Robert] (Series IA, Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Los Angeles Theatre Center, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 385)
    - The Lotos Club, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 386)
    - Luse, Geraldine, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 387)
    - Lutz, H.B., 1959 (Box 7, Folder 388)
    - [Lynn,] Jess, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 389)
    - M., Louis, Undated (Box 7, Folder 390)
    - M., Michael, Undated (Box 7, Folder 391)
    - MacArthur, Donald, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 392)
    - McCabe, Joe, 1994-1999, Undated (Box 7, Folder 393)
      The contents of this folder include the clipping "Putting Her Life on a New Course: A Shepherdstown Writer [Cheryl Royce]…," Elizabeth Bangs, Unknown Publication, Undated
    - [McCarter], Orville, Undated (Box 7, Folder 394)
    - McCarter Theatre Center for the Performing Arts, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 395)
    - Macer, Eugenia A., [1969] (Box 7, Folder 396)
    - MacInnes, Colin, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 397)
    - McIntosh, Ann, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 398)
    - The Macmillan Company, 1962-1992 (Box 7, Folder 399)
      The contents of this folder include signed copies of a contract regarding On Ice by Jack Gelber
    - McCord, Hancel, 1983-1985 (Box 7, Folder 400)
    - [McKeaney], Grace, Undated (Box 7, Folder 401)
    - McNally, Terrence, Undated (Box 7, Folder 402)
    - Macnaughton Lowe Representation Ltd., 1986-1989 (Box 7, Folder 403)
    - Madison, Ellen, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 404)
    - Magnum Photos Inc., 1988 (Box 7, Folder 405)
    - Mailer, Norman, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 406)
    - Malko, George, 1980, Undated (Box 7, Folder 407)
    - Mallin, Gail Kriegel, 1983-1984, Undated (Box 7, Folder 408)
    - Manhattan Theatre Club, 1978-1989 (Box 7, Folder 409)
    - Mann, Emily, Undated (Box 7, Folder 410)
    - Manning, Kara, 1994-1996, Undated (Box 7, Folder 411)
    - Manus, Willard, 1973-1999 (Box 7, Folder 412)
    - Marcus, Stevie, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 413)
    - Marguerite M. Andro, Attorney at Law, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 414)
    - Margulies, [David], 1976 (Box 7, Folder 415)
    - Margulies, Donald, 1978-1989 (Box 7, Folder 416)
    - Marks, Betty, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 417)
    - Marquand, John [Marquand], Sarah, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 418)
    - Marquis Who's Who, 1994-1995 (Box 7, Folder 419)
    - Marshall High School, Classes of January/June 1949, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 420)
    - Martef Theatre, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 421)
    - Matson, Lowell, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 422)
    - Mauroc, Daniel, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 423)
    - May, Judy, Undated (Box 7, Folder 424)
    - May, Ted S., 1992-1995 (Box 7, Folder 425)
    - [Meichese, Pauli], 1986 (Box 7, Folder 426)
    - Melfi, Leonard, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 427)
    - Melnick, Adam, Undated (Box 7, Folder 428)
    - Metronome, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 429)
    - Meyer, Richard, Undated (Box 7, Folder 430)
    - Meyer, Stewart, 1985-1990 (Box 7, Folder 431)
      The contents of this folder include the clipping Untitled [Review of Meyer's The Lotus Crew], Craig Rosen, LA Times Sunday Book Review, Feb. 3, 1985
    - Middhlar, C.W. Swetz van, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 432)
    - Millar, Stuart, 1950-1984, Undated (Box 7, Folder 433)
      The contents of this folder include a signed contract regarding "Mister Jelly Roll" and a photostatic copy of a clipping, "Stomping Piano Man [Review of Mr. Jelly Roll by Alan Lomax]," by Louis Armstrong, Unknown Publication, 1950
    - Miller, Jonathan, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 434)
    - Millstein, Bill, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 435)
    - Milwaukee Repertory Theatre Company, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 436)
    - Minkhoff, George Robert, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 437)
    - Mision Permanente de Cuba en las Naciones Unidas, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 438)
    - Mitchell, Adrian, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 439)
    - Molofsky, Merle, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 440)
    - Montana, Vivian, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 441)
    - Monte, Dan, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 442)
    - Moore, Honor, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 443)
    - Moore, Jane, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 444)
    - Morgenstern, Joseph, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 445)
    - Mori, Yasuhisa, Undated (Box 8, Folder 446)
    - Mosaic Theatre, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 447)
    - Motion Picture Health and Welfare Fund, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 448)
    - Moynihan, Donna S., 1985 (Box 8, Folder 449)
    - Mundari, Ingrid, Undated (Box 8, Folder 450)
    - Munro, Eleanor, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 451)
    - The Museum of Modern Art, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 452)
    - Nat, Lilah, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 453)
    - National Endowment for the Arts, 1974-1976 (Box 8, Folder 454)
    - Nedson, [Swan], 1997 (Box 8, Folder 455)
    - Nesson, Charles, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 456)
    - The New Attucks Theatre, 1976-1977, Undated (Box 8, Folder 457)
      This folder includes the following clippings: "The Tipster," Mary Dissen, Ledger Star, April 26, 1977, "'The Connection:' Good Show, Great Music," Ed Bacon, Ledger Star, April 19, 1977, "Jazz Play Transcends Crowd at Attucks," H.A. Cox, Journal and Guide, April 30, 1977
    - The New Dramatists Committee Inc., 1959-1985, Undated (Box 8, Folder 458)
    - New Earth Books, Undated (Box 8, Folder 459)
    - New Federal Theatre, 1980, Undated (Box 8, Folder 460)
      The contents of this folder include a signed and annotated contract regarding "The Connection"
    - Newgarden, Albert, 1990, Undated (Box 8, Folder 461)
    - The New Group, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 462)
    - Newman, Paul, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 463)
      See Also: "Starters" (Typescript) (Series II,I Box 27, Folder 988)
    - The New School for Social Research, 1969-1997 (Box 8, Folder 464)
    - New Theatre, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 465)
    - The New Theatre of Brooklyn, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 466)
    - Newton, Julia F., 1985 (Box 8, Folder 467)
    - The New Yorker, 1986-1988, Undated (Box 8, Folder 468)
    - New York Shakespeare Festival, 1979-1991 (Box 8, Folder 469)
    - New York State Council on the Arts, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 470)
      See Also: Williams, Galen (Series IA, Box 12, Folder 731)
    - New York State English Council, [1984] (Box 8, Folder 471)
    - New York University, 1983-1984, Undated (Box 8, Folder 472)
      See Also: "Starters" (Annotated Typescript) and Notes (Series II,I, Box 28, Folder 989)
    - Non-Traditional Casting Project, Inc., 1989 (Box 8, Folder 473)
    - Nordgreen, Olaf, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 474)
    - Northeastern Universty, Undated (Box 8, Folder 475)
    - Northlight Theatre, 1987, Undated (Box 8, Folder 476)
    - Ocaso, Jose, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 477)
    - Off-Off Broadway Alliance, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 478)
    - Oiust, Frank, 1976, Undated (Box 8, Folder 479)
    - Okita, Ron, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 480)
    - O'Rourke, William, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 481)
    - Orzil, Nick, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 482)
    - Ottenheimer, Albert M., 1972 (Box 8, Folder 483)
    - Owens, Rochelle, 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 484)
    - Packwood, Harry, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 485)
    - Papet, Sheila, Undated (Box 8, Folder 486)
    - Paramount Pictures Corporation, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 487)
    - The Paris Review, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 488)
    - Parker, Gilbert, 1959-1986 (Box 8, Folder 489)
    - Parra, Angelo M., Jr., 1997-1999 (Box 8, Folder 490)
    - The Paul Kohner-Michael Levy Agency, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 491)
    - Paul, Weiss, Rifkind, Wharton, and Garrison, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 492)
    - Pearlstein, Dennis R., Undated (Box 8, Folder 493)
    - Peerce, Larry, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 494)
    - P.E.N. American Center, 1978-1984 (Box 8, Folder 495)
    - Penn, Arthur, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 496)
    - Pennswood, Clara, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 497)
    - Perluck, Neil, Undated (Box 8, Folder 498)
    - Philadelphia Festival Theatre for New Plays, 1981-1987 (Box 8, Folder 499)
      This folder includes an unsigned contract regarding "Starters" by Jack Gelber and a letter from Dugald MacArthur; See Also: "Starters, Tues 4/6/82 Latest Revision" (Annotated Typescript) and Notes (Series II,I, Box 28, Folder 992)
    - Picus, Howard, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 500)
    - Pierce, Clara, Undated (Box 8, Folder 501)
    - Pinero, Miguel, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 502)
    - [Pinter], Arnold, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 503)
    - Pinto, Winokur, and Pagano, Certified Public Accountants, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 504)
    - Pittsburgh Public Theatre, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 505)
    - Planson, Claude, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 506)
    - Playboy Magazine, 1963-1966 (Box 8, Folder 507)
    - Playwirght's Horizons, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 508)
      See Also: Weiner, Edward Randall (Series IA, Box 12, Folder 717)
    - Playwrights Horizons Theatre School, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 509)
      The contents of this folder include a signed contract offering Gelber the position of "Instructor;" See Also: Weiner, Edward Randall (Series IA, Box 12, Folder 717)
    - Playwrights Unlimited, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 510)
    - Pleasance, Donald, 1962-1970 (Box 8, Folder 511)
      The contents of this folder include an unsigned contract regarding "The Apple"
    - Pogan, Lenny Pogan, Lillian, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 512)
    - Pontrelli, Mary, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 513)
    - Pope, Deborah J., [1978] (Box 9, Folder 514)
    - Poppleton, Pat, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 515)
    - Portland Stage Company, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 516)
    - Port Washington Public Schools, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 517)
    - Potash, June C., 1981 (Box 9, Folder 518)
    - Powell, Anthony, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 519)
    - Powell, J. Dakota, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 520)
    - Primary Stages, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 521)
    - Prince William Sound Community College, 1998-1999 (Box 9, Folder 522)
      For Oversize Material See: Series IA Oversize, Box 48, Folder 1193
    - Producer-Writer's Guild of America Pension Plan, 1971-1988 (Box 9, Folder 523)
    - Professional Staff Congress/ City University of New York, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 524)
    - The Public Theatre, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 525)
    - Puerto Rican Traveling Theatre Company, Inc., 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 526)
      The contents of this folder include a signed contract offering Gelber the position of Director for a production of "The Man and The Fly" by Jose Ruibal
    - Punch Productions, Inc., Undated (Box 9, Folder 527)
    - Pure Orange Productions, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 528)
      The contents of this folder include a signed agreement regarding "Chambers"
    - Racolin, Alexander E., 1994 (Box 9, Folder 529)
    - Rafelson, Bob, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 530)
    - Raymond Wagner Productions Inc. SI Litvinoff Productions Inc., 1967-1968 (Box 9, Folder 531)
      The contents of this folder include an unsigned contract, and a signed correction to it, offering Gelber the task of writing a screenplay, "Faith," for a film entitled Virtues
    - Redfield, William, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 532)
    - A Red Orchid Theatre, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 533)
      The contents of this folder include the following clippings: "New Theatre Premieres in Old Town," Lawrence Bommer, Chicago Tribune, February 19, 1993, "The Connection, A Red Orchid Theatre," Jack Helbig, Reader, February 26, [1993], "Red Orchid's Debut Unique, Depressing," Teresa Budasi, The Northwest Herald, February 26, 1993, "'Connection' Shows Its Age But It's Still Fascinating," Lawrence Bommer, Chicago Tribune, March 5, 1993, "In a Retro Decade the Beat Goes on Again," Leah Eskin, Chicago Tribune, March 12, 1993, "'The Connection' Addiction, Again," Wayne Scott, No Source, Undated; See Also May, Ted S. (Series IA, Box 7, Folder 425)
    - Reed, Richard Steele, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 534)
    - Reich, Ellen, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 535)
    - Reiter, Seymour, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 536)
    - Rember, John, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 537)
    - [Resnicoff, Desra H.], 1993 (Box 9, Folder 538)
    - Reynaud, Roseline, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 539)
    - Richardson, Anne, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 540)
    - Richardson, Jack, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 541)
    - [Riordon], Guy, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 542)
    - Rivera, Jose, 1983-1986, Undated (Box 9, Folder 543)
    - Robbins, Jane Marla, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 544)
    - Robert P. Reiter Attorney at Law, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 545)
    - Roberts, Ernesto, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 546)
    - The Rockefeller Foundation, 1971-1997 (Box 9, Folder 547)
    - Roeder, Anla, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 548)
    - [Roiphe], Anne, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 549)
    - Rosemont College, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 550)
    - Rosenau, Anita H., 1983-1985 (Box 9, Folder 551)
    - Rosenstone/Wender, 1984-1986 (Box 9, Folder 552)
    - Roslyn Targ Literary Agency, Inc., 1982 (Box 9, Folder 553)
    - Roth, Ari, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 554)
      The contents of this folder include a signed agreement regarding "Born Guilty" by Ari Roth
    - Royal National Theatre, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 555)
      See Also: Kustow, Michael (Series IA, Box 6, Folder 354); Rudman, Michael (Series IA, Box 9, Folder 557)
    - Royal Shakespeare Company, 1967-1998 (Box 9, Folder 556)
      See Also: Brook, Peter (Series IA, Box 2, Folder 89), Brooks, Jeremy (Series IA, Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Rudman, Michael, 1969-1998 (Box 9, Folder 557)
      See Also: International Creative Management (Series IA, Box 5, Folder 306)
    - Ruiz, Elizabeth, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 558)
    - Rutgers University, Undated (Box 9, Folder 559)
    - Ryan, Hon. William F., 1965 (Box 9, Folder 560)
    - S., Murray, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 561)
    - Sa'Adah, Rafael, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 562)
    - Sacks, Michael, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 563)
    - Sagaponack Films, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 564)